Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Accession 2016:065 FA1140
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Accession 2016:065
1950-1997
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1140
0.57 Cubic Feet
Arrangement
As received. The Catalogued Reports are arranged numerically by an arbitrary call number assigned during cataloging, from 1 to approximately 20,000.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Ford Foundation records were deposited at Rockefeller Archive Center in 2011. This material was transferred to RAC in 2016 as Accession 2016:065.
Scope and Contents
The Ford Foundation's Catalogued Reports collection includes policy and programming documents, program evaluations, and periodic program status reports produced by Foundation officers and staff, as well as consultants and grantees. Some published material produced by Ford Foundation grants is also included in the collection. The collection also includes some of the Ford Foundation's own publications, such as the Annual Reports and newsletters.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
In the early 1970s, the Ford Foundation's archives staff began to identify and catalog individual reports, policy and programming documents, and program evaluations in an effort to create an internal lending-library of useful documents. Many of the Catalogued Reports were physically culled from the former Foundation officers' and staff's archival collections of 'office files'. When those collections of 'office files' were later processed, and finding aids created, an appendix of "Reports Removed" (or, Reports Transferred") was added to the finding aids. By 1977 the collection included more than 3,500 reports, and by 1979 some 5,000 reports had been cataloged. Duplicated copies of the reports were also created on microfiche, and later microfilm.
Related Materials
For other collections of Ford Foundation Catalogued Reports, please refer to the following finding aids (arranged by Report Number): FA739A Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 1-3254 FA739B Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739C Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 6262-9286 FA739D Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739E Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 FA739F Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 FA739G Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 17727-19980
- The Community, Economy, and Environment Initiative: Lessons Learned from Organizational Change Activities v. 2 (Report 012839), 1996 December (Box 51761)
- On-Farm Research in Eastern India (Report 012764) (Box 51761)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Report is restricted from access.
- Creating Learning Partnerships: An Analysis of Problems and Prospects for Institutional Learning (Reports 012762) (Box 51761)
  Restricted from access.
- A Review of the Ford Foundation's Cultural Grantmaking in Asia v. 6 (Report 012594), 1994 January (Box 51761)
- The Challenge for the Decade of the 90's: A Survey of Trends and Issues Related to Refugees, Asylees, Migrants and the Internally Displaced (Report 012310), 1992 (Box 51761)
- The Challenge for the Decade of the 90's: A Survey of Trends and Issues Related to Refugees, Asylees, Migrants and the Internally Displaced v. 7 (Report 012310), 1992 (Box 51761)
- Evaluation of Evaluation: The Case of Follow-Through (Report 010366), 1978 (Box 51761)
- Forest for a Dynamic Kingdom: Support for the Emergence of Social Forestry in Thailand v. 9 (Report 012843), 1996 December (Box 51761)
- Java Social Forestry Program Institutional Evaluation v. 16 (Report 012269), 1991 (Box 51761)
- Challenging the Assumptions: An Analysis of the Role of Evaluation in the Ford Foundation's Work in Forestry v. 11 (Report 010865), 1985 (Box 51761)
- Forestry for Sustainable Rural Development v. 12 (Report 017120), 1998 (Box 51761)
- The Ford Foundation in India and Pakistan, 1952-1970 v. 13 (Report 001970), 1971 (Box 51761)
- Report on Selected Projects in Archives, Editing, Public History and Curriculum Development Funded by Ford Foundation v. 15 (Report 012838), 1997 December 15 (Box 51761)
- Judgement of Value: Choices to the Test, An Assessment of Project Evaluation in the Division of National Affairs of The Ford Foundation v. 19 (Report 002328) (Box 51761)
  Report is restricted from access
- Articles of Incorporation of The Ford Foundation (Report 019775), 1936 (Box 51762)
- The Ford Foundation Financial Statement (Reports 019776), 1950 December 31 (Box 51762)
- Staff Responses to Alexander Heard's September 24 Memorandum, "Next Steps in Planning for the Foundation's Future" Volume II (Report 019777) (Box 51762)
- Money in Search of a Mission: An Assessment of the use of a $10 million appropriation to Columbia University which led to establishment of its Urban Center (Box 51762)
- Proposal: A Comprehensive Funding and Conceptual Model for Arizona Job College Inc. (Report 019779), 1973 (Box 51762)